<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Baptiste Genest website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Baptiste Genest website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>XMin is the first Hugo theme I have designed. The original reason that I wrote it was I needed a minimal example of Hugo themes when I was writing the blogdown book. Basically I wanted a simple theme that supports a navigation menu, a home page, other single pages, lists of pages, blog posts, categories, tags, and RSS. That is all. Nothing fancy. In terms of CSS and JavaScript, I really want to keep them minimal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Here is a selection of my favorite and most polished projects/experiments over the last 5 years, sorted by period of interest (Most recent first).&#xA;Worst sorting algorithm ever but it&amp;rsquo;s an eigenvalue flow Given a time-valued matrix function A(t), its eigenvalues and eigenvectors evolve as.: $$ \dot{\lambda}_i = \langle \dot{A} n_i,n_i\rangle \\ \dot{n}_i = \sum \frac{1}{\lambda_i - \lambda_j} \langle \dot{A} n_i,n_j\rangle n_j $$&#xA;By setting A(t) = A_0 + t(B-A_0) we know that the eigenvalues of A(t) must interpolate between the ones of A_0 and B but by remaining sorted along the way since the repulsive potential 1/(\lambda_i - \lambda_j) must always be finite.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>BSP-OT: Sparse transport plans between discrete measures in loglinear time SIGGRAPH Asia 2025 (journal) - Baptiste Genest, Nicolas Bonneel, Vincent Nivoliers, David Coeurjolly&#xA;Best Paper Award Paper Supplementary Code Talk Replicability Stamp&#xA;Implicit UVs: Real-time semi-global parameterization of implicit surfaces Eurographics 2025 - Baptiste Genest, Pierre Gueth, Jérémy Levallois, Stephanie Wang&#xA;Paper (Submitted version) Supplementary Talk Fast Forward&#xA;Non-Euclidean Sliced Optimal Transport Sampling Eurographics 2024 - Baptiste Genest, Nicolas Courty, David Coeurjolly</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/software/</guid>
      <description> Slope Slope is a 3D slide engine built on top of Polyscope !&#xA;All my conference presentations have been with it and I&amp;rsquo;ve had some very nice feedback so feel free to check the software and the documentation!&#xA;Repo Documentation </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talks / Reports</title>
      <link>/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talks/</guid>
      <description>In french :&#xA;Introduction to Energy Methods : notebook Vector field synthesis, presentation of Discrete Connections and Vector Heat Method : pdf video Approximate convex decomposition, presentation of Approximate Convex Decomposition for 3D Meshes with Collision-Aware Concavity and Tree Search : pdf Introduction to applied Math : pdf Defense of the Voronoï integration project : notebook Introduction to stochastic calculus and applications to mesh-less PDEs : notebook In english :</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Formulaire de retour 2025 : LIFAPI (automne) : chargé de TP LIFAPC (printemps) : chargé de TD Annale corrigée 1er contrôle : sujet vidéo de la correction fiche recap Si je suis votre chargé de TD/TP : vous pouvez m&amp;rsquo;envoyer un message anonymement (si vous n&amp;rsquo;avez pas compris quelque chose, me faire un retour, des points d&amp;rsquo;améliorations, etc&amp;hellip; n&amp;rsquo;hésitez pas, c&amp;rsquo;est là pour ça !) Mot de passe :</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toffee</title>
      <link>/toffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/toffee/</guid>
      <description>A random Toffee picture to brighten your day.&#xA;ANOTHER ONE</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
