<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Baptiste Genest website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Baptiste Genest website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>XMin is the first Hugo theme I have designed. The original reason that I wrote it was I needed a minimal example of Hugo themes when I was writing the blogdown book. Basically I wanted a simple theme that supports a navigation menu, a home page, other single pages, lists of pages, blog posts, categories, tags, and RSS. That is all. Nothing fancy. In terms of CSS and JavaScript, I really want to keep them minimal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Here is a selection of my favorite and most polished projects/experiments over the last 5 years, sorted by period of interest (Most recent first).&#xA;Lattice Boltzman Method (LBM) Canonical solver of the LBM in D2Q9.&#xA;Two Relaxation Time (TRT) method for the collision operator. Dirichlet boundary conditions: $$ f_i(x,t) = f_i^{eq}(\rho,\vec{0}) \text{, } x\in \partial \Omega. $$ Curl visualized in blue/red. Amazing resources: book blog.&#xA;Markov-Chain Diffusion-Limited-Aggregation (MCDLA) A Markov Chain interpretation of the DLA process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description> Non-Euclidean Sliced Optimal Transport Sampling Eurographics 2024 - Baptiste Genest, Nicolas Courty, David Coeurjolly&#xA;Günter Enderle Award for the Best Paper PDF VIDEO CODE Copy BibTeX Erratum Replicability Stamp </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talks / Reports</title>
      <link>/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talks/</guid>
      <description>In french :&#xA;Introduction to Energy Methods : notebook Vector field synthesis, presentation of Discrete Connections and Vector Heat Method : pdf video Approximate convex decomposition, presentation of Approximate Convex Decomposition for 3D Meshes with Collision-Aware Concavity and Tree Search : pdf Introduction to applied Math : pdf Defense of the Voronoï integration project : notebook Introduction to stochastic calculus and applications to mesh-less PDEs : notebook In english :</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Formulaire de retour 2025 : LIFAPC (printemps) : chargé de TD Si je suis votre chargé de TD/TP : vous pouvez m&amp;rsquo;envoyer un message anonymement (si vous n&amp;rsquo;avez pas compris quelque chose, me faire un retour, des points d&amp;rsquo;améliorations, etc&amp;hellip; n&amp;rsquo;hésitez pas, c&amp;rsquo;est là pour ça !) Mot de passe :&#xA;Envoyer</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toffee</title>
      <link>/toffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/toffee/</guid>
      <description>A random Toffee picture to brighten your day.&#xA;ANOTHER ONE</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
